Unable to make their own toxins, these females resort to drinking the blood of other fireflies to get these protective chemicals. So a firefly vampire, brought to you by natural selection. We still have a lot to learn about fireflies, but it looks like many stories will remain untold, because around the world, firefly populations are blinking out. The main culprit: habitat loss. Pretty much everywhere, the fields and forests, the mangroves and meadows that fireflies need to survive, are giving way to development and to sprawl. Here's another problem: we've conquered darkness, but in the process, we spill so much extra light out into the night that it disrupts the lives of other creatures, and fireflies are especially sensitive to light pollution because it obscures the signals that they use to find their mates. Do we really need fireflies? After all, they're just one tiny bit of Earth's biodiversity. Yet every time a species is lost, it's like extinguishing a room full of candles one by one. You might not notice when the first few flames flicker out, but in the end, you're left sitting in darkness. As we work together to craft a planetary future, I hope we can find a way to keep these bright lights shining. Thank you. (Applause)
Incapaces de fabricar sus propias toxinas, estas hembras recurren a beber la sangre de otras luciérnagas para conseguir sus sustancias protectoras. Se trata de una luciérnaga vampiro, creada por la selección natural. Aún tenemos mucho que aprender de las luciérnagas, pero puede que muchas historias se queden sin contar porque en todo el mundo, las poblaciones de luciérnagas están emitiendo luces de emergencia. El mayor culpable: la pérdida de su hábitat. Casi por todas partes, los campos y los bosques, los manglares y las praderas que las luciérnagas necesitan para sobrevivir, están dando paso al desarrollo y la expansión urbanística. Y he aquí otro problema: hemos conquistado la oscuridad, pero en el proceso, producimos tanta luz adicional en la noche que perturbamos la vida de otras criaturas, y las luciérnagas son especialmente sensibles a la contaminación lumínica porque oscurece las señales que ellas usan para encontrar a sus parejas. ¿Necesitamos realmente a las luciérnagas? Después de todo, no son más que una parte diminuta de la biodiversidad terrestre. Aunque cada vez que una especie desaparece, es como apagar una habitación llena de velas una a una. Puede ser que no lo notemos cuando las primeras llamas se apaguen, pero al final, estaremos sentados en la oscuridad. Ya que estamos trabajando juntos para construir el futuro del planeta, confío en que encontremos la forma de mantener estas luces encendidas. Gracias. (Aplausos)